hey guys coach break address quick video
on some thoughts I've been having about
deathless you know particular importance
first thing I want to talk about is up
is something that I hear from a lot of
strength coaches who I highly respect
I've got a ton of respect for a couple
of guys who will tell you this but I
just want to offer a different
perspective a lot of people will say
when you line up for a deadlift you know
maximum deadlift just come down pick the
bar up and pull it as fast as possible
so you'll watch them do their their
heaviest pulls and they'll just be like
yeah now that obviously works well for
them and I would venture to guess that
probably fifty percent of people are
going to do well with that strategy the
theory is that then you utilize the
stretch reflex apply now can't go down
there how much but I think probably the
other fifty percent of people probably
going to do better by camping down there
for a little bit longer I'm not limited
by the stretch shorting cycle I've got
to like get my mind right and get a
tight grip and I wait for the feeling to
come if you watch a lot of dead lifters
in powerlifting contest they do that
they wait they don't think of time zones
the weightlifters they will take their
time down there so try both ways and
figure out what's best for you when I do
a maximum debit you know I will line up
I'll get my grip I'll get set with all
my legs around and then I'll pump my
legs a few times until I feel right so
that's thought number one try both ways
see what you like the most but don't be
afraid to take your time down there if
that helps you second thought I get a
lot of emails for people who will ask me
you know take can you look at my form
but I don't think like your form is
dependent upon your goal so if if your
goal is to maximize transfer is for or
to minimize the potential for injury or
to look as pretty as possible then I
would say you know keep your back is
arched as possible keep your neck act
you know so you look like this this
would be your setup right here you know
yeah but if your goal is to maximize
lifting poundage and justice item if you
go to powerlifting competitions you'll
notice this probably you know seven or
eight out of ten of them they round
they're out there back and they relax
their shoulders and most of the best
Dillinger's in the world do that too so
if your goal you know let's say you're a
500 pound
you want to get to 600 see just like a
lot of power lifters who start out
bodybuilding and do the narrow stance
squats you know to try to target
applause once they learn to get a wider
stance and sit back you know it first
it's harder but over time they can get
to it can climb in which are powder to
assume things same thing with the devil
if you get to a point where instead of
lining up like this you round your upper
back not my lower back my lower back
stays but you just round the upper back
and instead of getting the shoulders
back and pull them down right here that
is the style the most people will find
over time maximizes the weight that they
can lift for the deadlift so anyway
those are just a couple of quick shots
hope you enjoy the video